<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Hardware on KN100 | Kevin Norman</title>
    <link>https://kn100.me/tags/hardware/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Hardware on KN100 | Kevin Norman</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2020 21:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://kn100.me/tags/hardware/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Why Does My Computer Not Boot with a USB Hub Attached?</title>
      <link>https://kn100.me/usb-hub-bs/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2020 21:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kn100.me/usb-hub-bs/</guid>
      <description>My trusty old USB 3 hub has failed. It was only around a year old, but it was cheap and it worked. It wasn&amp;rsquo;t powered, but most of the time it didn&amp;rsquo;t need to be. One day I began having very strange issues with USB on my computer. Devices randomly disconnecting, devices never connecting until the computer was rebooted and so on. I eventually narrowed it down to the hub. I tossed it out after a quick internal inspection had revealed nothing obviously wrong, and went shopping for a new hub.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>News in the Morning: A Simple Hack</title>
      <link>https://kn100.me/news-in-the-morning-a-simple-hack/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Jun 2018 19:43:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kn100.me/news-in-the-morning-a-simple-hack/</guid>
      <description>Like many people, I find it difficult to wake up in the morning. I want to automate some of the things I do in the morning in order to continue to hack away at my laziness.
To this effect, I want my television to switch on and over to BBC news in the morning. Unfortunately, Hisense do not provide a way to control the television remotely as far as I can tell, and nmapping it doesn&amp;rsquo;t give me anything too interesting.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Cybiko, a Forgotten Gem</title>
      <link>https://kn100.me/the-cybiko-a-forgotten-gem/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Mar 2018 11:59:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kn100.me/the-cybiko-a-forgotten-gem/</guid>
      <description>Few remember the Cybiko. In the year 2000, a Russian company unveiled a very strange looking device, adorned with a comically small keyboard and a retro antenna. They called it a handheld computer. They marketed it towards teens with some of themost insane advertising I&amp;rsquo;d personally ever seen.
The device was an interesting one, and to describe just how far ahead of its time it really was, it will be useful to draw comparisons against smartphones of today.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
