<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Stories on KN100 | Kevin Norman</title>
    <link>https://kn100.me/tags/stories/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Stories on KN100 | Kevin Norman</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 22 Jul 2019 10:19:34 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://kn100.me/tags/stories/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>How Do I Make Breaking Changes in Go Without Annoying People?</title>
      <link>https://kn100.me/making-breaking-changes-in-go/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jul 2019 10:19:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kn100.me/making-breaking-changes-in-go/</guid>
      <description>Knowing when and how to make breaking changes is tough. It is even tougher in the Go ecosystem. After being burned by making a breaking change and annoying people, I&amp;rsquo;m going to investigate how best to mitigate this annoyance.
 Disclaimer: This is mostly opinion, and only my opinion. This post is not associated with my employer in any way. You can contact me @normankev141
 What even is a breaking change, anyway A simple definition of a breaking change is any change you make to your code that could break other code which directly or indirectly depends on it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exploiting UPnP, Literally Childsplay.</title>
      <link>https://kn100.me/exploiting-upnp-literally-childsplay/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jul 2019 14:20:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kn100.me/exploiting-upnp-literally-childsplay/</guid>
      <description>As a kid, I used to love playing Minecraft. I was technically precocious from a fairly young age, and naturally gravitated to attempting to host my own Minecraft server for me and my band of geeky pals to play on. The problem was, I had no idea what port forwarding was, nor how to log into a router. The solution I found was about as novel as it was dumb.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Those Damn Romanians and Their Damn Data Protection Laws.</title>
      <link>https://kn100.me/those-damn-romanians/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2019 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kn100.me/those-damn-romanians/</guid>
      <description>A long time ago I worked for an ISP as Tier 1 technical support. This is just one of many stories I have from my time here. These were originally published elsewhere on the internet, but are being reworked and republished here.
Sometimes, the degree of insanity in a conversation can reach such a fever pitch that it is hard to recover. Sometimes, people can say things that leave you so flabbergasted that you aren&amp;rsquo;t sure if you&amp;rsquo;re being trolled or not.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Beating Round-Trip Latency With Redis Pipelining</title>
      <link>https://kn100.me/redis-pipelining/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2019 19:59:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kn100.me/redis-pipelining/</guid>
      <description>I worked on a task which involved checking every single value in a Redis instance, and modifying ones which matched a certain format. This script needed to run in a fairly timely fashion, as it would need to be run frequently. Making requests sequentially didn&amp;rsquo;t cut it, so I learned about pipelining. This simple optimization meant that a script which I originally calculated to take over 50 hours to run ran in under 4 minutes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>That Time a Sticker Made Me an Accidental Domain Squatter</title>
      <link>https://kn100.me/the-accidental-domain-squatter/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Apr 2019 22:56:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kn100.me/the-accidental-domain-squatter/</guid>
      <description>It all started with my noticing of these stickers absolutely everywhere all over London. I&amp;rsquo;d also seen them in other European cities. I was never curious enough to actually search for it, so I just noticed and moved on. The method by which I discovered their true meaning was something I never expected.
  The sticker in question
  Every now and then I&amp;rsquo;d come across one and the question would briefly pop back into my head, but it&amp;rsquo;s surprising how high the barrier to looking something up is for me.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
