<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Nostalgia on KN100 | Kevin Norman</title>
    <link>https://kn100.me/tags/nostalgia/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Nostalgia on KN100 | Kevin Norman</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 05 Jul 2019 14:20:41 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://kn100.me/tags/nostalgia/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Exploiting UPnP, Literally Childsplay.</title>
      <link>https://kn100.me/exploiting-upnp-literally-childsplay/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jul 2019 14:20:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kn100.me/exploiting-upnp-literally-childsplay/</guid>
      <description>As a kid, I used to love playing Minecraft. I was technically precocious from a fairly young age, and naturally gravitated to attempting to host my own Minecraft server for me and my band of geeky pals to play on. The problem was, I had no idea what port forwarding was, nor how to log into a router. The solution I found was about as novel as it was dumb.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NotSoEducated – A Project From a While Ago</title>
      <link>https://kn100.me/notsoeducated-a-project-from-a-while-ago/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jun 2018 21:22:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kn100.me/notsoeducated-a-project-from-a-while-ago/</guid>
      <description>A while ago, I and a friend of mine got rather annoyed at a ridiculous propaganda attempt regarding e-cigarettes, so we countered it by parodying the complete lies with a well cited, truthful account. They&amp;rsquo;ve long since taken the site down, I suspect in response, but you can somewhat experience it thanks to the Wayback Machine.
  A poster designed for the project   </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Cybiko, a Forgotten Gem</title>
      <link>https://kn100.me/the-cybiko-a-forgotten-gem/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Mar 2018 11:59:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kn100.me/the-cybiko-a-forgotten-gem/</guid>
      <description>Few remember the Cybiko. In the year 2000, a Russian company unveiled a very strange looking device, adorned with a comically small keyboard and a retro antenna. They called it a handheld computer. They marketed it towards teens with some of themost insane advertising I&amp;rsquo;d personally ever seen.
The device was an interesting one, and to describe just how far ahead of its time it really was, it will be useful to draw comparisons against smartphones of today.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
